kitchens.com 2019-05-21

# Privacy Policy - Content - Kitchens.com

This Privacy Policy was last updated May, 24, 2018.

**1\. General Privacy Policy Matters.**   At Kitchens.com, we take the privacy of our users very seriously. This Privacy Policy is a part of our Terms of Use. It describes how and why we collect, use, and disclose information about you in connection with your use of our services, including those offered through our websites, emails, and mobile applications (collectively, the "Site"). The terms "we", "us", and "our" refer to Kitchens.com. When you use the Site, you consent to our collection, use, and disclosure of information about you, including information that may be considered personal data, as described in this Privacy Policy.

**2\. Information We Collect. **We collect and store information from or about you:

(a) when you directly provide it to us. This happens when you:

(i) register or create an account (e.g., your name);  
(ii) purchase services or products (e.g., your billing information, including your address and credit card number);  
(iii) request assistance from our customer support team (e.g., your phone number);  
(iv) complete contact forms, request newsletters or other information, or participate in contests and surveys (e.g., your email address);  
(v) create a public profile, communicate with other users and third-parties through the Site, and make public contributions to the Site (e.g., the profile photo you upload, or comments you post); or  
(vi) otherwise participate in activities we promote that require information about you.

(b) automatically, when you use and interact with the Site. Automatically collected information includes:

(i) your general activity on the Site (e.g., your viewing history and search activity, including the date and time the Site was used);  
(ii) identifiers such as an anonymized session identifier;  
(iii) your geographic location. We use this data to provide you with location-based services (such as advertising and personalized content). Most mobile devices allow you to control or disable the use of location services for applications in the device's settings;  
(iv) website traffic volume, frequency of visits, and type and time of transactions you initiate through the Site (e.g., when you add your company's website to "Find a Pro");  
(v) information regarding your interaction with email messages (e.g., whether you opened, clicked on, or forwarded an email message);  
(vi) your Internet Protocol (IP) address;  
(vii) the type and settings of the device, operating system, and browser used to access the Site; and  
(viii) other information gathered through cookies and similar technologies, which are discussed further in the fourth section of this Privacy Policy, entitled "Cookies and Similar Technologies".

(c) From other sources. We may also receive information about you through:  

(i) Sign-In Accounts: If you sign up for Kitchens.com using a third-party Site or application such as Facebook Connect or Google Plus or link your Kitchens.com account to your account with a third-party Site such as Facebook or Google, we may receive information about you from such third-party website. You can control the information that we receive from such third-party website using the privacy and data settings on the third-party's website.  
(ii) Service Providers. We may also receive information about you from our service providers and business partners, including companies that assist with payment processing, analytics, data processing and management (e.g. to measure ad quality and responses to ads, and to display ads that are more likely to be relevant to you) account management, hosting, customer and technical support, and other services which we use to personalize your Site experience.

**3\. How We Use Your Information.  **We use information about you for several general purposes:

(a) to operate, maintain, and optimize the Site and your account;  
(b) improve the quality and types of services that we deliver;  
(c) to diagnose problems with and identify any security risks, errors, or needed enhancements to the Site;  
(d) to provide you with technical support;  
(e) to contact you for feedback or conduct research about Kitchens.com's customer base or Site;  
(f) to process payments and provide you with the services you've paid for or requested;  
(g) to notify you of technical updates or changes in policy;  
(h) to process contests, sweepstakes, or other promotions and fulfill any related awards or discounts;  
(i) to understand and analyze how you use our Services and what products and services are most relevant to you;  
(j) to collect aggregate statistics about use of the Site; and  
(k) to analyze and develop our marketing strategy.

**4\. Cookies and Similar Technologies **. 

(a) What are Cookies? 

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. These text files can be read by these websites and help to identify you when you return to a website. Cookies can be "persistent" or "session" cookies. Persistent cookies remain on your computer when you have gone offline, while session cookies are deleted as soon as you close your web browser. To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to block and delete cookies, please visit <http://www.aboutcookies.org/>.

(b) Other Technologies: 

(i) We use cookies and similar technologies (such as action tags, also known as beacons, or pixels tags) for a number of purposes, including to remember preferences, track conversions, conduct marketing and promotional efforts, analyze site traffic and trends, and generally understand the online behaviors and interests of people who interact with our Site.  
(ii) We use third-party advertising companies to serve advertisements on our behalf. These companies may use a cookie or an action tag to tailor the advertisements you see on this website and other sites, to track your response to their advertisement, to determine whether advertising has been served and to measure the effectiveness of their advertising.  
(iii) We use third-party analytics service providers to assist us in collecting and understanding website usage information. We use information from these services to help us improve our website and the services we provide to our users.

(c) By using the Site, you agree to our use of these tracking technologies.  

**5\. Sharing. We may share information about you with the following third parties:**

(a) Service providers: We share your personal data as necessary for any third party to provide services associated with the Site, including to provide measurement and analytic services. These third parties (and any subcontractors) are subject to strict data processing terms and conditions and are prohibited from utilizing, sharing or retaining your personal data for any purpose other than as they have been specifically contracted for (or without your consent).  
(b) Other networks and connected apps: If you choose to connect your account to other apps or social networks such as Facebook or Twitter, you will be sharing certain information with these apps or networks. Kitchens.com is not responsible for these other apps or networks, so make sure you only connect your account with apps or services that your trust.  
(c) Advertisers: We allow advertisers and associated third parties to collect and use information they need to ensure their ads are properly served and to measure the success of their campaigns on websites and apps.  
(d) Other users: information in your public profile and in comments you post will be accessible by other users of the Site.  
(e) Corporate Affiliates: We may share information with our corporate affiliates, parents and/or subsidiaries.  
(f) Other circumstances that you expressly consent to.  
We may also share information about you in the following contexts:  
(g) Pursuant to an investigation: We may investigate and disclose information from or about you if we have a good faith belief that such investigation or disclosure (a) is reasonably necessary to comply with legal process and law enforcement instructions and orders, such as a search warrant, subpoena, statute, judicial proceeding, or other legal process served on us; (b) is helpful to prevent, investigate, or identify possible wrongdoing in connection with the Site; or (c) protects our rights, reputation, property, or that of our users, affiliates, or the public.  
(h) Pursuant to a business transfer: We may share information from or about you with our parent companies, subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under common control, in which case we will require them to honor this Privacy Policy. If another company acquires Kitchens.com or all or substantially all of our assets, that company will possess the same information, and will assume the rights and obligations with respect to that information as described in this Privacy Policy.  
(i) As Anonymized Data: We frequently aggregate personal data in a way that makes it impracticable to use that data to identify a particular person; we also sometimes maintain individual data records with personal identifiers removed, and maintain in a manner in which it is impracticable to relink it to any particular individual. In this Privacy Policy, we refer to such data as "Anonymized Data" and do not consider it to be personal data. We may use Anonymized Data in order to create statistical information regarding the Site and its use, which we may then share with third parties.

**6\. Social Media Features and Widgets. **Our Site may integrate with social sharing features or other related tools which let you share actions you take on our Site with other apps, sites or media, and vice versa. These features may enable the sharing of information with your friends or the public, depending on the settings you establish with the social sharing site. For example, you may click on a Facebook "like" button, which publishes to your Facebook account that you "like" one of the pictures or profiles featured on the Site. These features may also collect your IP address and which page you are visiting on our Site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Your interaction with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the relevant social sharing site. Please refer to the privacy policies of those social sharing sites for more information. As stated below, we cannot control Site visitors' and users' use of any such information or content you choose to make available publicly.

**7\. Controlling Your Personal Data. **  

(a) In order to process your personal data, we rely on your consent or our legitimate interests to process to process your data. You may withdraw your consent or object to the use of our personal data at any time, but you will may longer be able to access the Site.  
(b) Other users may be able to identify you, or associate you with your account, if you include personal data in the content you post publicly. We are not responsible for, and this Privacy Policy does not apply to, information you choose to post publicly.  
(c) Please note that the Site may contain links to unaffiliated third-party sites. Except as set forth herein, we do not share your personal data with them, and are not responsible for their privacy practices. We suggest you read the privacy policies on or applicable to all such third-party Sites.  
(d) If you register an account, you may manage the content and information you share when you use the Site through your account settings, including for the features explained below. You are solely responsible for keeping your settings up-to-date.  
(e) Once accounts can be created on the Site, you can adjust your privacy settings by following the appropriate links on our Site or by contacting us. All commercial emails and newsletters also allow you to unsubscribe at any time.  
(f) To control cookies, you can modify your settings in most web browsers to accept or deny cookies or to request your permission each time a site attempts to set a cookie. You can also manually delete previously stored cookies at any time. Please note that if you choose to block cookies, doing so may impair the Site or prevent certain elements of it from functioning.

**8\. Data Retention and Account Termination. **Once accounts can be created on the Site, you will have the ability to close your account by following the appropriate links on our Site, or by contacting us (see "Contact Information"). Once your account is closed, your profile will no longer be viewable, , but we may retain information about you for the purposes authorized under this Privacy Policy, unless prohibited by law. For example, we may retain information to prevent, investigate, or identify possible wrongdoing in connection with the Site or to comply with legal obligations. The time-period for which we keep information varies according to the information's use. In some cases, there are legal requirements to keep data for a minimum period. Unless there is a specific legal requirement for us to keep the information, we plan to retain it for no longer than is necessary to fulfill a legitimate business need. Please also note that even after you have deleted your account, your photos, reviews and other content associated with your use of the Site may still be accessible and viewable in accordance with applicable law and our Terms of Use. We may maintain Anonymized Data, including usage data, for analytics purposes.

**9\. Children. **The Site is not directed to children under 16 and children under 16 are not permitted to use the Site. We do not knowingly collect personal data from children under 16. If you become aware that a child has provided us with personal data without parental consent, please contact us (see "Contact Information"). If we become aware that a child under 16 has provided us with personal data without parental consent, we take steps to remove such information and terminate the applicable account.

**10\. Security.**  We use commercially reasonable efforts to follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the Personal Data submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. However, no method of transmission over the Internet or via mobile device, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect information about you, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

**11\. Location of Data and Transfers of Information.**   This website is owned and operated by White Picket Media, Inc. d/b/a Kitchens.com, which is located in the United States. If you are located outside of the United States, please note that personal data will be processed in the cloud by our cloud service provider (currently Heroku, which sits on top of Amazon Web Services), which offers sufficient guarantees to implement appropriate technical and organizational safeguards that meet the GDPR's standards. We have a data processing agreement in place with our cloud service provider, ensuring compliance with the GDPR and, in the event of any unauthorized access to, or use of, personal data, the appropriate authorities will be notified. All information is transmitted to us by our cloud service provider, will be processed in the United States, and will be handled and protected under the terms of this Privacy Policy and applicable U.S. laws, which may not be as protective as the laws in your country. By using the Site, you agree to this.

**12\. EEA Users.**   Kitchens.com endeavors to be fully compliant with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), effective as of May 25th, 2018. Kitchens.com may act, depending on the circumstances, as either or both a Controller and a Processor of personal data (as these terms are defined in the GDPR). We act as the Controller of information that we ask you to provide to create an account and information that we automatically collect when you use the Site. We act as the Processor of user-generated content and information provided to us by third parties or other websites.

EEA users have the right to request access to personal data, as well as to seek to update, delete or correct their personal data. You can usually do this using the settings and tools provided in your Services account. If you cannot use the settings and tools, contact us for additional access and assistance.

**13\. Your California Privacy Rights.**   California Civil Code Section § 1798.83 permits California residents that are users of our Site to request certain information regarding our disclosure of Personal Data to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an e-mail to [dpo@kitchens.com](mailto:dpo@kitchens.com).

**14\. Modifications to this Privacy Policy.**   We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you through our mobile app, by email or by posting a notice on the Site. Your continued use of the website after a revision to the Privacy Policy indicates your acceptance and agreement to the current Privacy Policy. We recommend that you periodically review the Privacy Policy to make sure you understand and are up-to-date on how we're keeping your information safe.

**15\. Contact Information.**   If you have any further questions regarding our privacy practices or information about you, please feel free to contact us by email at: [info@kitchens.com](mailto:info@kitchens.com), or in writing, or by phone at:

Kitchens.com  
19701 Bethel Church Rd., Suite 103-305  
Cornelius, NC 28031  
Telephone:  773-769-8400

**Kitchens.com**. also has a "Data Protection Officer" who is responsible for matters relating to privacy and data protection. This Data Protection Officer can be reached at the following email address: [dpo@kitchens.com](mailto:dpo@kitchens.com)

This Privacy Policy was last updated: May 24, 2018
